Guide to the Wheeler family papers, 1811-1934
Wheeler family papers, 1811-1934
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Wheeler family papers, 1811-1934.
3878
Wheeler family.
1.2 cubic ft.
Financial and legal documents, accounts, genealogies, correspondence, writing drafts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes family Bible and genealogical records, financial and legal records and drafts of George Downs Wheeler's autobiography.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes a draft and revision of George Downs Wheeler's autobiography; herd records kept by Charles A. Wheeler; legal documents; family Bible records; genealogy; letters; financial records; and other family papers. Other names in the collection include W. (Mollie) Wheeler; W. A. Gregory; Charles P. Knapp; Henry M. Gregory; William Oringron; Silas Crandall; Thaddeus Mather; William Hawley; William Wheeler; Royal Wheeler; Robert Turner; James Turner; Mrs. George Hewitt; John Peters; Rachel Crandall; Addison J. Wheeler; Asa Babcock; and John Dickinson.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wheeler family.; Babcock, Asa.; Crandall, Rachel.; Crandall, Silas.; Dickinson, C. J. (John); Gregory, Henry M.; Gregory, W. A.; Hawley, William.; Hewitt, George,; Knapp, Charles P.; Mather, Thaddeus.; Oringron, William.; Peters, John.; Turner, James.; Turner, Robert.; Wheeler, Addison J.; Wheeler, Charles A.; Wheeler, George Downs.; Wheeler, Royal.; Wheeler, W.; Wheeler, William.
Form and Genre Terms:
Autobiographies.; Genealogies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Related Documents
  - Genealogical material (Bible records) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Genealogy and copies of letters (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Mrs. George W. (Mollie) Wheeler from W.A. Gregory, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Commencement program, Deposit Academy, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photography of Charles P. Knapp (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Autobiography of George Downs Wheeler (pen), 1898 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Autobiography of George Downs Wheeler (pencil), 1898 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Receipts from Henry M. Gregory, 1811-1818 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cleveland Lumber, 1811, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Record of sale of village lots, 1813-1818 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Patent: William Oringron, Delaware Township, Pike County, PA, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Silas Crandall Estate, 1818-1832 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Thaddeus Mather and William Hawley, 1823-1825 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - William and Royal Wheeler, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Robert and James Turner and William Wheeler and Co., 1833-1837 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - House above Mrs. George Hewitt's house, 1836-1847 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Road to McClure, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kidder accounts - leather and shoes, 1840-1843 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - William Wheeler and John Peters, 1840-1845 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Orders of Treadwell, First Presbyterian Society of Tompkins, 1819-1820 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notes and judgements - Orin Day, Catskill, 1822-1827 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dusenbary (?) and Wheeler, 1825-1832 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Accounts: land at Smithville, Chenango County, 1828-1832 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Crandall, widow Rachel and children, 1837-1840 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Errors in deeds and maps, Genesee, Allegany County, 1841-1847 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Addison J. Wheeler papers, 1841-1892 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cable lot on Wheeler Street, 1847-1848 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Asa Babcock estate, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - John Dickinson estate, 1812-1830 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Other Documents
  - 1814-1819 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1820-1823 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1824-1829 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1830-1833 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1834 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1835-1838 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1840 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1841 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1842 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1843 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1844 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1845-1846 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1847-1878 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1849 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1850-1856 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1861-1866 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1867-1869 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1870 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1873-1878 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1881-1882 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1883-1889 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Farm accounts, 1836-1894 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Deposit Farmers' Club, 1884-1889 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Herd record - C.A. Wheeler, 1886-1906 (Box 4, Folder 1)